KASHISH **KHARBANDA**

A self-driven digital native carrying a high level of enthusiasm for Information Technology and Entrepreneurship. Well-versed with Computer Science and Data Science principles. 4 years of tutoring experience in the CS landscape, 3 years of experience interning in the industry, 2 years of experience in leadership roles. Growth minded with a vision of creating an impact. A people person looking for opportunities that leverage strong leadership and collaborative skills!

Contact

🟠 Greater Seattle Area



🦲 (404) 518-0072



🔽 kashishkhar@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/kashishk/



🔗 <u>kashishkhar.github.io/profile/</u>

Skills

Professional

Leadership Willingness to learn Communication Dependability Time Management

Technical Java Python Pandas, Numpy, MatPlotLib Technology Blogging SQL, PostrgeSQL Git Cloud, Data Migration MS Office

Education

University of California, Berkeley Aug 2019 - May 2023

Computer Science, Data Science Certificate of Entrepreneurship&Tech

Relevant coursework:

- Structure/Interpretation of Computer **Programs**
- Data Structures
- Foundations of Data Science
- Principles/Techniques of Data
- Designing Information Devices and Systems (I & II)
- Introduction to Entrepreneurship

North Creek High School

Sep 2017 - June 2019

High School Diploma

Organizations: Future Business Leaders of America, Technology Student Association, HOSA, Girls Who Code, National Honor Society, American Cancer Society, **KANSHU2** Tutoring

Experience

Summer Extern

AT&T Corporation

Jun 2020-Aug 2020

Certified for 80 hours of IT, Business, and Professional Development training.

Al Platform Intern

Microsoft Corporation

June 2019-August 2019

Used Python and SQL to understand the unexpected change of data features overtime and learned how to address the resulting model accuracy degradation.

Data Science Intern

Microsoft Corporation

Jun 2018-Aug 2018

Worked on Data Migration and SKU Recommendation to predict the best Azure SQL Database SKU for an on-premises database; used Python, C#, SQL, U-SQL in Azure Data Lake, and PostgreSQL.

Extracurriculars

Data Science Research Mentor

Undergrad Laboratory @ Berkeley

Sep 2020-present

Research mentor in Data Science division; responsible for leading and mentoring 4-5 students for research project being presented in May 2021.

External Events & Partnerships

Opportunity Through Data

Sep 2020-present

Part of strategic operations team with the vision of improving access to Data Science education, particularly in underrepresented communities.

Committee Member

FEMTech @ Berkelev

Sep 2019-present

2019 | Managed financial sector of club (budgeting, reimbursements). 2020 | Hosting career-related events for females in Technology/STEM.

Founder & President

FBLA @ North Creek High School

Sep 2017-Jul 2018

Founded school's FBLA chapter by establishing the chapter's authenticity and legacy. Led more than 100 members as President.

Projects

Stock Market Prediction

In Progress

As part of UC Berkeley's Data Science Society, used a 64-feature Open High Low Close stock market dataset for 10 NASDAQ-100 companies to extract the technical indicators needed to predict stock market trends.

Facial Detection

June 2020

Learned about Computer Vision and utilized Machine Learning based Haar Cascade classifiers with Adaboost to identify objects in images and videos, particularly human facial features.

Inclusive Meeting

Used Natural Language Processing to perform sentimental analysis on team meeting conversations and gauge certain factors such as tone of speaker, productivity of meeting, etc. Also learned about data privacy.

Activities and Awards

- **Juni Learning** | CS instructor for Python, Java, and AP CS [present]
- Google NCWIT | Award recipient
- Mobile Application Development | Top 15 at FBLA Nationals
- Relay for Life cancer nonprofit | Team captain, Social Media Lead
- Girls Who Code | Volunteer and Tutor